[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trient tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I have already
published 54 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level Concepts from couple of sessions
onwards have started teaching you
realtime scenarios where you might
encounter different obstacles while
automating your test cases and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases so this is
our lesson 55 in terms of overall trient
tosa training and this is our lesson 13
or it's obstacle 13 in terms of realtime
scenarios
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
you this lesson I'm going to teach you a
realtime scenario where you need to
extract the random numbers from a
lengthy text string by using named group
method within regular expression so now
let us see how can we solve for this
obstacle let us first understand what is
the obstacle in
detail so this is our next
obstacle named named as tough cookie and
categorized as hard so let us go for
it so here the obstacle is obstacle is
random text string
so this particular text box generates a
random text string as soon as you click
on it so the first edit box displays a
random text that includes three large
numbers extract the numbers from the
string and enter each into the according
text box let's see here as soon as I
click on this first text box I can see
there are three large numbers this is my
first large number and this is my second
large number and this is my third large
number what I need to do I need
to extract my first large number and
enter into the first edit box and second
large number extract this enter here and
third large number EXT extract from this
and enter in the third edit box so
that's the challenge let's see how we
can solve for this let us go to trient
tasa so as usual so we are going to
capture all the test objects under
folder called obstacles right so this is
where we are capturing all the objects
for each obstacle I'm going to use the
same folder so what I'm going to do here
right click on obstacles folder select
scan
application and this is the application
that I would like to capture right scan
the
application here I would like to capture
the objects what are those objects my
first text box second third fourth there
are four different text boxes so here
click me to reveal that is my first text
box and then enter first number this is
my second text box so all these objects
are getting uniquely identified you can
see here the selected item is unique and
third
one the selected item is unique the same
way fourth one so four objects we
captured now let us copy this obstacle
name so that we can name name the module
with the obstacle name here paste it
here okay now you can
save this
module and then close X scan if you go
back you go back to trient tasa so this
is the obstacle that we captured just
now okay let's see here see click me to
reveal so we have total four edit boxes
now let's go to left panel where we have
a test cases to select this obstacles
folder and here here we are automating
all the test cases right under this
obstacle right click and then select
create test case and name this with the
same name that we captured obstacle name
double click on this particular test
case
now to automate your test case first we
need to drag the module that we captured
onto the test
case what should we do first our first
step is you need to click on this text
box to generate
the random text okay for that here what
I'm going to do here
simply
enter click okay and then your action
mode should be input right so once once
you click on this now you need to
extract only you need to extract only
number portions my first number second
third for that I need to add the module
one more time let's drag this module and
drop onto the test case one more time
because I need to use this text box
again that's why what I'm going to do
here here to extract the text
large number
text in three different groups we need
to use regular expression and number
grouping so
let's let me show you the regular
expression that I would like to
use so this is very big regular
expression so I already copied the
regular expression but don't worry I'm
going to explain this regular expression
in detail okay so this is my regular
expression I'm using regular
expression and this cap symbol is your
regular expression starts from
here dot star question mark this is any
text I'm considering any text I mean any
string right and then here is my first
number group where I'm actually
capturing that first number to a buffer
number called number one and what is
that number format my number format is 0
to
9 and then I'm concatenating it so
that's why I'm using plus and then again
after number you will have some text
again right so that's why I'm denoting
it as dot star question mark and then my
second number group will start that
represents number two because I'm
extracting number two and storing into a
buffer called number two and what is the
format of number two 0 to 9 and
concatenate it and then again you will
have a text random text so that's why
dot star question mark and then you have
third number group I'm storing that
number into a number three
buffer and the format is 0 to9
concatenate it and then again you will
have a text any text right it can have
any text and your dollar symbol is end
of your regular expression beginning of
regular expression is Cap dollar is end
of your regular expression that means
end of your text let me go back to a
presentation and let me explain in
detail again what is this regular
expression so here you can see at the
bottom I have a regular expression okay
reg X this is the method that we use for
tonoscope and you can see here cap
symbol this asserts the position at the
start of the string that means this is
my first start of the s that means this
is the start of the string and then dot
star question mark this matches any
character except for the line Terminator
that means except it don't con accept
your next line it's going to consider
only the text that is in the same line
okay and
then from here question mark number 1 0
to 9 this represents this is a named
capturing group that matches one or more
digits from 0 to 9 the captured digits
are stored in a group named number one
this is your buffer again you have do
star question Mark again this matches
any character Zero or more times right
and then again number two group so
another named capturing group that
matches one or more digits which is 0 to
9 and then you have text one more time
this matches any character
02 this matches any character Zero or
more times and then you have number
three named group number three named
capturing group and then
star and then dot star question mark and
dollar symbol so this matches any
character Zero or more times up to the
end of the string so dollar represents
your end of the string now let's go back
to
trica so now once we extract three
different grouped
numbers three different number groups
now it's time for us to enter into the
text
box so here we need to enter in these
boxes the three group numbers so now
here this is my first group so what I'm
going to do I'm going to call a buffer
because I'm
storing into a buffer called number one
so I'm calling buffer number
one close C close Square bra sorry for
number one so whenever you call a buffer
open curly braces capital B close Square
braces sorry open Square braces your
buffer name close Square braces close
curly braces the same way number two
open curly braces will be open Square
braces number two close Square braces
close curly
braces then again
number three which is capital
B number three is my
buffer close Square braces close curly
braces now let us save this particular
test case and change the work state as
completed right now let me try let me
run and
see whether it works or not okay right
click
and run in
scratchbook so it is failed let us see
why the test case is failed okay let's
go back to our trient tasa to see what
is wrong with the script here I can see
input is not supported for regular
expression values I understand now so if
you see here I'm using regular
expression I cannot use action mode
input I have to use action mode
verify what it does it's going to verify
the entire text and it extracts the
numbers into these buffer groups okay so
now let so now let's save the script let
me try running the script one more time
see it clicked on this and it entered
all
three number groups all or all three
large numbers into the corresponding
edit box you solve this automation
problem so hope you all understand the
concept of
extracting the number groups from a
large text by using number group and the
regular expression if you have any
queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
ques
[Music]